activemusician.com 2007-12-11

# Privacy Statement

## Site Information

| 

**Privacy Statement**

|  • Introduction  
• What Information Do We Compile?  
• How do we internally use the data about our customers and visitors?  
• Do we allow an opt-out from the collection of data on an individual?  
• Protection and Security of Customer Information  
• Feedback  
  
---  
**1\. Introduction**  
ActiveMusician provides interactive services on the Internet to enable customers to learn more about music and to purchase musical products that interest them at affordable prices. To promote trust and confidence in the Internet and in ActiveMusician, we are providing a full disclosure of our privacy practices and information uses. 

One of our goals at ActiveMusician is to respect the privacy rights of anyone who visits or purchases products from the ActiveMusician site. Except as set forth within this privacy statement, we do not release personally identifiable information about our individual customers and visitors without their permission. The information you enter on our site is held in confidence between you and us and ActiveMusician does not sell, trade, or rent your personal information to others. We do collect information from our customers and visitors, which is used to process orders and to improve the ActiveMusician shopping experience. The following is a statement of the use of the information that we collect, and if or how any of it is disseminated. 

If you feel that ActiveMusician has violated this Statement on Privacy in any way, please contact us at [orders@activemusician.com](mailto:orders@activemusician.com?subject=Privacy), so that we may address this issue. Please note that the information provided in this Statement relates only to ActiveMusician's policies and practices. ActiveMusician is not responsible for the content or the privacy policies of Web sites to which it may link.  
Return to the Top  
  
**2\. What Information Do We Compile?**  
When you order, we need to know your name, e-mail address, mailing address, credit card number, and expiration date. This allows us to process and fulfill your order and to notify you of your order status. When you sign up for our free newsletter or other information services, we need only an e-mail address, which we use to send the information you requested. If you refer someone to our site through the ActiveMusician "Tell a Friend About This" service, we ask for your e-mail address and that of the recipient in order to complete your request. We will never disclose or send promotional e-mail to recipient addresses provided only through this service. 

For everyone who visits the ActiveMusician domain, we log IP addresses, the type of operating system that the visitor's computer uses, and the type of browser software used by the visitor. From the IP address, we can determine the Internet Service Provider and the geographic location of the visitor's point of connectivity. We do not log IP addresses to track a user's session, nor do we link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable. 

ActiveMusician currently uses cookies to save a customer's shopping cart, to track site usage, and to give you better, more personalized service. A "cookie" is a file transferred from a website to the hard drive of your computer so that the website may track your activities on the website. A cookie will not let a website know any personally identifying information about you, such as your real name, address, etc., unless you previously provided that information at the website or have set your preferences in your browser to provide that information. ActiveMusician is not generally interested in any one individual and does not collect personally identifiable information about any one person using cookies. We use this information for internal use only; we don't share it with others.  
Return to the Top  
  
**3\. How do we internally use the data about our customers and visitors?**  
We generally use the aggregate data we collect to evaluate the extent to which the ActiveMusician website continues to be useful and relevant to our customers and the general public, and to help us develop the design and layout of the store. For example, we may perform statistical analyses of the collective characteristics and behavior of our customers and visitors, to measure overall user demographics and interests regarding specific areas of the ActiveMusician domain and to analyze how and where to use our resources. We may also use the aggregate data collected to inform any sponsors and/or advertisers as to the profile and number of people who have seen and clicked on their advertisement. No personally identifiable information will be disclosed to any sponsor or advertiser as part of this process; only information in an aggregate form. Without the data collected, we would not know what the most popular sections of ActiveMusician are, we would not be able to provide an effective forum for sponsors to advertise in, nor would we be able to measure the effectiveness of any possible promotions. 

We may also use the information we collect to occasionally notify you about important functionality changes to the Web site, new services, and special offers we think you'll find valuable. If you would rather not receive this information, our order form provides an immediate option to not receive it, or you can instead send a blank e-mail message to news[at]activemusician.com (replace "[at]" with "@" before sending) and include the words "unsubscribe" in the subject heading of your message. If you use more than one email address, remember to send this message from each email address that you have given to us. 

ActiveMusician does not share any personally identifiable information with outside parties for commercial purposes, unless stated at the time of collection. The option is given to customers and visitors, at the time of collection, not to allow ActiveMusician to share such information with outside parties. If customers or visitors opt for such an option, we will not share such information with outside parties; however, we do reserve the right to release that information concerning a customer when the customer partakes in an illegal activity, or for a customer who we believe is in violation of our Terms of Use, even without a subpoena, warrant, or other court order. ActiveMusician hopes that all customers, visitors and third parties adhere to our policies regarding the privacy of our customers; however, ActiveMusician does not assume any responsibility for any actions of third parties.  
Return to the Top  
  
**4\. Do we allow an opt-out from the collection of data on an individual?**  
During the order placement process for a customer, we do require that customers supply personal information. The fields that we require to be completed include billing address, shipping address, e-mail and payment information. This information is required in order to place, fulfill and confirm your order. We also ask if that customer would like to periodically receive promotional e-mail about products or services offered by ActiveMusician or its partners. If the customer would not like to receive these promotional mailings, he or she may opt out and select not to receive them. If at any time a customer would like to receive or defer these mailings, he or she can subscribe or unsubscribe by sending a blank e-mail message to news[at]activemusician.com (replace "[at]" with "@" before sending) and including the words "subscribe" or "unsubscribe" in the subject heading of the message. 

By using our web site, you consent to the collection and use of the information specified above by ActiveMusician. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page and also post a revision notice on the home page. Our goal is to keep customers aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it.  
Return to the Top  
  
**5\. Protection and Security of Customer Information**  
When you place an order at ActiveMusician, your personal information and credit card information is safe. That's because we've taken steps to ensure a secure and superior shopping environment. We use state-of-the-art secure socket layer (SSL) encryption technology that protects the transmission and storage of your credit card information. Your credit card number is not stored in our database.  
Return to the Top  
**6\. Feedback**  
ActiveMusician welcomes your questions and comments about privacy. Please send an e-mail to [orders@activemusician.com](mailto:orders@activemusician.com?subject=Privacy).  
Return to the Top
